William H. Ryder Collection of Confederate History MS011
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
William H. Ryder Collection of Confederate History
1860 -- 1875
1770 -- 1940
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Ryder, William H., Reverend
MS011
4.7 Linear Feet 5 boxes
181 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Cartes de Visite - Photographs; Documents inventoried in 'A Calendar of the Ryder Collection of Confederate Archives at Tufts College'; and Other identified Ryder material.
Custodial History
The Ryder Collection of Confederate Archives derives its name from its original collector, Reverend William H. Ryder, the Pastor of St. Paul's Church in Chicago. Ryder held this pastorate during the time that included the civil war. It was because of his work with the American Sanitary Commission, an agency not unlike the present-day Red Cross, that the Ryder Collection came to be.
In April of 1865, Ryder obtained permission to travel behind Confederate lines to engage in relief work on behalf of the Sanitary Commission. While engaged in this activity he also began to collect artifacts and other material for the upcoming North West Sanitary Fair to be held in Chicago. Since the Confederacy had collapsed only a few days before his arrival, Ryder found the capital at Richmond, Virginia in a state of considerable confusion. In the Capital building, documents were scattered over several of the office floors indicating the haste with which the place had been abandoned. Ryder gathered as many of these documents as he could handle and sent them back to the north. Upon Ryder's death, this collection was given to Tufts College, founded as a Universalist institution, as he was a clergyman of that faith.
As of 2012 there is no precise inventory documenting all items of the gift for was precise information contained in his will. At the time the library mentioned the Ryder donation in its Annual Report 1889 as containing "1441 volumes of books, 112 pamphlets, 101 numbers and a great quality of Confederate newspapers and documents, cases and a fine portrait." (UA137.003.005.00048). Therefore, we still do not know what the collection actually contained originally and where the remaining material is (clearly more than cataloged in this collection).
On February 26 2014, Susanne Belovari found six library cataloging cards listing particular issues of three Confederate newspapers (1864-1865) once part of the Ryder collection and kept in the library vault in the 1960s.
Scope and Contents
This collection largely consists of material collected by William H. Ryder, who traveled to Richmond as an agent of the Sanitary Commission in 1865 to collect material for the upcoming Sanitary Commission Fair. The material was donated to Tufts upon his death. Included are records of the Confederate government, letters, reports, receipts, loans, prison reports, Register of Treasury notes, a War registry, artifacts, and other materials pertaining to the Civil War. The bulk of the materials date from 1860 to 1875. Also included is a collection of cartes de visite of military leaders from the Confederacy and the Union during the Civil War, as well as images of European rulers, academics, artists, workers and a few unidentified women from the mid to late 19th century. This collection was surveyed as part of the Historical Records Survey project of the Work Project Administration in 1940.
Biographical / Historical
William Henry Ryder was born in Provincetown, Massachusetts July 18, 1822 of Universalist parents. His father was Captain Godfrey Ryder, a prominent Universalist on Cape Cod. William was trained at Pembroke, NH and his theological preparation for the ministry was at Clinton, NY. He was ordained at Concord, NH on October 11, 1843 where he continued as pastor. In 1846 he took charge of the parish at Nashua and on resigning his charge there made an extensive tour abroad visiting Palestine and spending seven months in Germany to study. On his return, he took charge of the church at Roxbury, Mass. where he remained ten years. In 1860 he became pastor of St. Paul's Church Chicago holding the position until 1882 when he resigned. Harvard College conferred on him the degree of AM in 1860 and Lombard University that of DD in 1863.
Reverend Ryder was a strong supporter of the Union cause during the Civil War. He agreed to travel to Richmond as an agent of the Sanitary Commission at the end of the war to collect material for the upcoming Sanitary Commission Fair, and while there discovered a famous letter used by the government in the Lincoln assassination trial.
Dr. Ryder was an eminently successful preacher and pastor, renown for his involvement in interests at home and in foreign missions. He was extremely shrewd in his financial investments, so that upon his death he was able to make generous bequests to the General Convention, Lombard University, St. Paul's Church Chicago, First Universalist Society Provincetown Mass., Illinois Universalist Convention, the Divinity Schools at St. Lawrence, Tufts, Lombard Buchtel College, and the Universalist Publishing House. He died in Chicago on March 7, 1888 in his 66th year.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Other Finding Aids
A printed catalog of the collection resulting from the survey of the Historical Records Survey project of the WPA called 'A Calendar of the Ryder Collection of Confederate Archives at Tufts College' (1940) serves as the online catalog to the documents and is available as online pdf in the DL; a physical copy is available in the DCA reading room.
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Civil War
- Cartes de Visite - Photographs, 1770 -- 1890; MS011.001; 1.45 Linear Feet; 180 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains cartes de visite of military leaders from the Confederacy and the Union during the American Civil War (1861-1865) as well as images of European rulers, academics, artists, workers and a few unidentified women. Cartes de visite are from Europe and the US and most individuals are identified in pencil on the back of each card, presumably in Ryder's handwriting. Also contained are a partial list of photographs and two handwritten notes referring to 'Civil War Acc't. Book [J. W. Randolph book-plate]' and 'Ryder Civil War Acct. Book. Treasury notes'.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Prof. O. [Oliver] Stearns, 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00001; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. O. Stearns." Produced by: Warren, Post Office Block, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Stearns, Oliver, 1807-1885
  - Andrew Johnson, 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00002; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Johnson, Andrew; 1808-1875; Only Southern senator in U.S. Senate; loyal to Union; he stayed while other S.'s left; Dec. 1860-1862; Military gov. of Tenn.; March 1862-1865; Vice president of the U.S.; 1865; President of the U.S.; April 15, 1865."
    Presidents--United States; Politicians; cartes-de-visite; Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875
  - Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00003; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Burnside; Burnside, Ambrose Everett; 1824-1881; Major General (Union Army); March 18, 1862." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881
  - Wilkes Booth [John], 1860 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00004; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Wilkes Booth." Produced by: Black & Case Photographic Artists, Boston & Newport, R.I.
    Actors; cartes-de-visite; Booth, John Wilkes, 1838-1865
  - Gen. Sherman [Thomas West], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00005; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "name?; Gen. Sherman."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Sherman, Thomas W. (Thomas West), 1813-1879
  - Gen. McLellan [sic, McClellan, George Brinton], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00006; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "McClellan, George Brinton; 1826-1885; General-in-Chief (Union Army); 1861-1862."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; McClellan, George Brinton, 1826-1885
  - Florence Nightingale, 1856; MS011.001.001.00007; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Miss Nightingale; Florence Nightingale." Produced by: H. Lenthall, Successor to Mr. Kilburn, Registered, 222. Regent Street LONDON.
    Nurses; cartes-de-visite; Nightingale, Florence, 1820-1910
  - Dix, John Adams, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00008; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Dix, John Adams; 1798-1879; Secretary of the Treasury (Union); Jan. 1861- Mar. 5, 1861.; Major General (Union Army); 1861- ." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    cartes-de-visite; Dix, John Adams, 1798-1879
  - Gen. Curtis [Samuel Ryan] of Missouri, 1861 -- 1866; MS011.001.001.00009; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "General Curtis; General- Union; Curtis, Samuel Ryan; 1805-1866." Produced by: Snyder, Black & Sturn, N.Y.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Curtis, Samuel Ryan, 1805-1866
  - Gen. Burnside [Ambrose Everett], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00010; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Burnside, Ambrose Everett; 1824-1881; Major Gen'l (Union Army); March 18, 1862."
  - Her Majesty. [Queen Victoria], 1860; MS011.001.001.00011; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Victoria." Produced by: Mayall, 224 Regent Street, London.
    Queens (people); cartes-de-visite; Victoria, Queen of United Kingdom and Ireland, and Empress of India (1819-1909)
  - Pce et Pesse Napoleon [Prince Napoléon Joseph Charles Paul Bonaparte and Princess Princess Maria Clotilde of Savoy], 1860 -- 1878; MS011.001.001.00012; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "(Jan 1878.; Pce et Pesse Napoleon." Clipping from newspaper article pasted on back of card. Produced by: Disderi & C. Photographes de S. M. L'empereur, 8 Boulevart des Italiens, Paris.
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Bonaparte, Napoléon-Joseph-Charles-Paul, Prince, 1822-1891
  - Palmerston [Henry John Temple, 3rd Viscount], born at Broadlands, Hampshire, 1784., 1859 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00013; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: John Watkins, Parliament Street; London Stereoscopic Comp. 54 Cheapside (2 Doors from Bow Church): Under the Patronage of Her Majesty. These date are approximate.
    Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865
  - A. [Arthur] Schopenhauer, 1855 -- 1860; MS011.001.001.00014; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "A. Schopenhauer." Produced by: Hof-Photograph Hermann Günther früher Werderscher Markt No. 6, jezt [sic; now]: Ziethenplatz No. 2, Berlin.
    Philosophers; cartes-de-visite; Schopenhauer, Arthur, 1788-1860
  - Mrs. Scott Siddons [Mary Frances], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00015; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Mrs. Scott Siddons; Actress." Produced by: Gurney, Fifth Avenue, Cor. 16th St, N.Y.
    Actresses; cartes-de-visite; Siddons, Mary Frances Scott-, 1844-1896
  - Gen. Nelson [William] under Buell [Incorrect identification, unknown person], 1860 -- 1862; MS011.001.001.00016; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find pict of Gen Nelson; General William Nelson; Union General 1824-1862 Kentucky; 'Bull Nelson'." The person pictured does not match other pictures of General "Bull" Nelson and is probably incorrectly identified. Identity remains unknown. Produced by: Snyder, Black & Sturn, N.Y.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Nelson, William, 1824-1862
  - Garibaldi [Giuseppe], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00017; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Garibaldi." Produced by: Duroni & Murer, Opticiens Photographes, De S. M. Le Roi D'Italie. Paris, 12, Rue Vivienne. Milan, 11, Corso Vitt. Emanuel.
    cartes-de-visite; Garibaldi, Giuseppe, 1807-1882
  - Victor-Emmanuel II, King of Italy, 1861 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00018; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Victor Emanuel; King of Italy, 1861; died 1878." Produced by: Bulla Frères, Editeurs Photographes, 16, Rue Tiquetonne, Paris.
    Kings (people); cartes-de-visite; Victor Emmanuel II, King of Italy, 1820-1878
  - President James Walker, 1852 -- 1860; MS011.001.001.00019; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "President Jas (James) Walker; 1794-1874; Pres. of Harvard 1852-60." Produced by: Warren, Post Office Block, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    cartes-de-visite; Walker, James, 1794-1874
  - Prof. Convers Francis, 1850 -- 1860; MS011.001.001.00020; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. Convers Francis; 1795-1863; Prof. Harvard Divinity School; 1842-1863." Produced by: Warren, Post Office Block, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Francis, Convers, 1795-1863
  - Washington Elm? [Incorrect identification, Tree at Harvard], 1864; MS011.001.001.00021; Warren, George Kendall (Box 1)
    25. "Washington Elm? Cambridge." Produced by: Warren, Post Office Block, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Trees; cartes-de-visite
  - Dr. Adler [Rabbi Dr. Nathan Marcus], 1873 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00022; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: The London Stereoscopic & Photographic Company. 110 & 108, Regent Street and 54, Cheapside.
    cartes-de-visite; Adler, Nathan Marcus, 1803-1890
  - Joh. Ed. [Johann Eduard] Erdmann, 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00023; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Joh. Ed. Erdmann." Produced by: Anders-Paltzow, Halle A.S.
    Philosophers; cartes-de-visite; Erdmann, Johann Eduard, 1805-1892
  - Prof. Theoph. [Theophilus] Parsons, 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00024; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof Theoph. Parsons." Produced by: Warren, Post Office Block, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Parsons, Theophilus, 1797-1882
  - Prof. A. [Andrew] P. Peabody, 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00025; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. A. P. Peabody." Produced by: George K. Warren, Photographer, Post Office Building, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Peabody, Andrew P. (Andrew Preston), 1811-1893
  - Prof. G. R. [George Rapall] Noyes, 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00026; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. G. R. Noyes." Produced by: Warren, Photographer, Post Office Building, Cambridgeport, Mass.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Noyes, George Rapall, 1873-1952
  - Michael Corcoran, prisoner at Richmond, 1861 -- 1863; MS011.001.001.00027; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "name? Michael Corcoran; Union general; 1827-63; Ireland."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Corcoran, Michael, 1827-1863
  - Hunter, David, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00028; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Hunter, David; 1802-1886; Brig. Gen'l (Union Army); 1861-1864; Pres. of courts martial; Feb. 1, 1865-." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Hunter, David, 1802-1886
  - Gen. Hunter [David], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00029; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Hunter, David 1802-1886; Brigadier general (Union army) 1861-1864; Pres. of courts martial Feb. 1, 1865- ."
  - Kilpatrick, Hugh Judson, 1862 -- 1872; MS011.001.001.00030; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Kilpatrick, Hugh Judson 1836-1881; Major-general Mar. 13, 1865." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Kilpatrick, Hugh Judson, 1836-1881
  - Lyon [Nathaniel], 1861; MS011.001.001.00031; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Lyon, Nathaniel 1818-1861; Brigadier General (Union Army) May 1861."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Lyon, Nathaniel, 1818-1861
  - Meade, George Gordon, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00032; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Meade, George Gordon 1815-1872; Major-general (Union Army) Aug. 18, 1864- ." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Meade, George Gordon, 1815-1872
  - Gen. Rosecrans [William Starke], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00033; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Rosecrans, William Starke 1819-1898; Brigadier general (Union Army) 1861-1865; Major General-brevet (inactive) rank 1865."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Rosecrans, William S. (William Starke), 1819-1898
  - Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00034; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Sheridan; Sheridan, Philip Henry 1831-1888; Major-General (Union) Nov. 8, 1864- ."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888
  - Thomas, George Henry, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00035; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Thomas, George Henry 1816-1870; Major general (Union Army) 1865." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Thomas, George Henry, 1816-1870
  - Warren, Gouverneur Kemble, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00036; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Warren, Gouverneur Kemble 1830-1882; Major-gen'l (Union Army) Mar. 13, 1865- ." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Warren, Gouverneur K. (Gouverneur Kemble), 1830-1882
  - Gen. Halleck [Henry Wager], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00037; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Halleck, Henry Wager 1815-1872; Military advisor to the president with the title of General-in-Chief July 11, 1862- Mar. 12 1864."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Halleck, Henry Wager, 1815-1872
  - Halleck, Henry Wager, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00038; Unknown (Box 1)
    "Halleck, Henry Wager 1815-1872; Military advisor to the Pres. with title of General-in-Chief July 11, 1862- Mar. 12 1864." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
  - Howard, O. O. [Oliver Otis], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00039; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Howard, O. O. (gen.) 1830-1909; Brigadier gen'l (Union) with brevet rank of Major gen'l 1864." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Howard, O. O. (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909
  - Gilmore, Q. A. [Quincy Adams], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00040; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Gilmore, Q. A. (gen.); find biog of." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Gilmore, Q. A. (Quincy Adams), 1825-1888
  - Gen. Fremont [John Charles Frémont], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00041; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Fremont, John Charles 1813-1890; Major-General in chge of dept. of the West 1861- ."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Frmont, John Charles, 1813-1890
  - Gen. Banks [Nathaniel Prentiss], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00042; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss 1816-1894; Major-General (Union Army) May 16, 1861- ."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894
  - Com. Goldsborough [Louis Malesherbes], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00043; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Goldsborough, Louis Malesherbes 1805-1877; Commander (Union Navy) 1861-; (Atlantic Blockade); 1862- N. Atlantic Blockade Squadron; Rear Admiral 1862-1865 (inactive); 1865- (active)."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Goldsborough, Louis Malesherbes, 1805-1877
  - Gov. Sprague [William] of R. I., 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00044; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find another pict. of; one in Saudburg; William Sprague; Was governor of Rhode Island 1830-1915; R. I. Married Kate, daughter of Salmon P. Chase."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Governors; cartes-de-visite; Sprague, William, 1830-1915
  - Jas [James] A. Mulligan fought at Lexington, Missouri, captured, 1861 -- 1864; MS011.001.001.00045; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Mulligan, James A.; Find biog. of; James Adelfort Mulligan; Union Officer 1830-64; N.Y."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Mulligan, James Adelbert, 1830-1864
  - F. [Franz] Sigel, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00046; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Franz Sigel; Union General 1824-1902; Germany."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Sigel, Franz, 1824-1902
  - Winthrop [Theodore], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00047; Unknown (Box 1)
    25.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Lawyers; cartes-de-visite; Winthrop, Theodore, 1828-1861
  - Major-General John Gray Foster, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00048; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find pict of; Foster; Major-General John Gray Foster; Union General 1823-74; N.H.; U.S. M.A. Graduate Engineer." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Foster, John Gray, 1823-1874
  - Schiller [Friedrich], 1780 -- 1805; MS011.001.001.00049; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Schiller; Schiller." These dates are approximate and refer to the painting, not the carte-de-visite.
    Poets; Philosophers; Historians; cartes-de-visite; Schiller, Friedrich, 1759-1805
  - Cardinal Wiseman [Nicholas Patrick], 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00050; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Wiseman; English Cardinal; b. 1802; d. 1865." Produced by: Herbert Watkins, 215, Regent Street, London.
    Cardinals (prelates); cartes-de-visite; Wiseman, Nicholas Patrick, 1802-1865
  - [Pope] Pius IX. 1846-1878, 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00051; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Pius IX; 1846 (elected Pope) -1878 (died)."
    Popes; cartes-de-visite; Pius IX, Pope, 1792-1878
  - Cardinal Newman [John Henry], 1870 -- 1885; MS011.001.001.00052; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "born 1801; made Cardinal 1879." Produced by: H. J. Whitlock, 11 New Street, Birmingham.
    Cardinals (prelates); cartes-de-visite; Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890
  - His Eminence Cardinal Newman, 1873 -- 1885; MS011.001.001.00053; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "born 1801; made Cardinal 1879." Produced by: The London Stereoscopic & Photographic Company. 110 & 108, Regent Street and 54, Cheapside.
  - Rosa Bonheur, 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00054; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Rosa Bonheur." Produced by: Disderi & C. Photographes de S. M. L'empereur, 8 Boulevart des Italiens, Paris.
    Artists; cartes-de-visite; Bonheur, Rosa, 1822-1899
  - Cardinal Antonelli [Giacomo], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00055; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Antonelli; Italian Cardinal; Secretary of State and confidential adviser of Pope Pius IX; born 1806; died 1876; C'al Antonelli."
    Cardinals (prelates); cartes-de-visite; Antonelli, Giacomo, 1806-1876
  - J. [John] Russell; born in London 1792, entered parliament 1813, 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00056; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: London Stereoscopic Comp. 54 Cheapside (2 Doors from Bow Church): Under the Patronage of Her Majesty.
    Statesmen; Prime Minister; cartes-de-visite; Russell, John Abraham, 1792-1865
  - G. [Giuseppe] Garibaldi; photographed on board H.M.S. "Hannibal" at the capitulation of Palermo, 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00057; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Under the Patronage of Her Majesty. Album Portraits, London Stereoscopic Comp. 54 Cheapside (2 Doors from Bow Church).
    Military; cartes-de-visite; Garibaldi, Giuseppe, 1807-1882
  - Bismark [sic, Bismarck, Otto von], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00058; Unknown (Box 1)
    Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Bismarck, Otto, Fürst von, 1815-1898
  - Dr. Artom [Rev. Dr. Benjamin], 1873 -- 1879; MS011.001.001.00059; Unknown (Box 1)